## **Matthew Suttie**

Junior Web Developer

Github: github.com/ChronoLogic12 Website: matthewsuttie.com email: msuttie12@hotmail.com

Location: Monmouth, Wales Mobile: 07908147256

I am a junior web developer experienced with HTML, CSS, Javascript and Python and have recently completed a level 5 NVQ in web development with Code Institute. I have completed several projects, both front end and full stack, gaining a broad knowledge of coding languages and frameworks. With proficiency in Adobe Photoshop and Adobe XD and almost eight years of experience in specialised, customer facing roles, I am excited to apply myself toward a new opportunity in tech.

### **Technical Skill Set**

#### **Technologies** Databases Frameworks / Libraries **Version Control/Hosting** JavaScript MongoDB Django Git MySQL HTML5 Flask Github CSS3 jQuery Heroku Python Materialize Netlify Bootstrap Cloudinary

Stripe

AWS S3

## **Education & Training**

2021-2022 Code institute - Level 5 NVQ - Diploma in Web App Development

2015 Ceritech Audio - Level 2 NVQ - Customer service

A Levels Music Technology, Music, Physics, Biology

GCSE 11 of grade C or above including Maths and English

# **Technical Courses Completed**

2019+ Codecademy
 2018-2019 Codecademy
 Waitrose - Internal qualification
 Javascript, C#, CSS, SCSS, RegEx and others
 Fruit, Vegetable and Horticulture Specialist

# Portfolio Projects

For a full list of previous projects including links to live and demo sites as well as their code repositories please see my portfolio site.

- Tippy E-commerce site for a fictional tea subscription service offering world class tea delivered monthly.
   Technologies Used HTML5, CSS with Materialize, JavaScript, Python, Django framework, Postgres DB, Stripe API for payments and AWS for hosting media.
   GitHub https://github.com/ChronoLogic12/tippy-tea-subscription
- BookMarks Online book recommendation and review site.
   Technologies Used HTML5, CSS with Materialize, JavaScript, Python, Flask framework, MongoDB.
   GitHub <a href="https://github.com/ChronoLogic12/bookmarks">https://github.com/ChronoLogic12/bookmarks</a>
- Spaceman Interactive Javascript based variation on the classic game, Hangman.
   Technologies Used HTML5, CSS, JavaScript with ¡Query.
   GitHub <a href="https://github.com/ChronoLogic12/spaceman">https://github.com/ChronoLogic12/spaceman</a>
- 4. Green Lawns Web and graphic designer Commercial site for a local dog boarding kennels. Technologies Used - Adobe XD, Adobe Photoshop. Live Site - <a href="https://greenlawnskennels.co.uk/">https://greenlawnskennels.co.uk/</a>

# **Professional Experience**

Waitrose & Partners 2015 – 2021

Fruit, Vegetable and Horticulture Specialist

I worked as a specialist promoting and managing fresh produce and training partners (employees) to meet company standards.

### Key responsibilities

- Engaging and advising customers to enhance their shopping experience.
- Driving and improving sales through the application of specialist product and service knowledge.
- Improving personal and team knowledge through partner training and development of documentation.
- Implementing stock management techniques to reduce waste and increase profitability.

### Greenlawns Kennels (live site)

2020

Web & Graphic Designer

I worked in a two person team to design and develop a website for a local business.

### Key responsibilities

- Creating both low and high fidelity wireframes.
- Designing page layouts, UX and colour schemes using Adobe XD.
- Creating all custom graphics using Adobe Photoshop and sourcing 3rd party icons and images.
- Editing images provided by the client for use within the site.
- Working closely with the lead developer throughout the full development process.

Ceritech Audio 2013 – 2015

**AV Sales Consultant** 

In this role I developed an expansive product knowledge of high end Hi-Fi and home cinema to design and sell custom audiovisual solutions.

#### Key responsibilities

- Creating bespoke audiovisual solutions to satisfy customer specifications.
- Demonstration, Installation and configuration of digital systems.
- Collaborating with expert team members to ensure customers receive their desired outcomes.
- Meeting and learning from suppliers to expand product and industry knowledge.

# Interests & Additional information

- I participated in the Code Institute Pride Hackathon; Our project 'Light Up' won 2nd place!
- I am currently studying React and have created a TTRPG aid using the framework.
- I am a passionate musician and play the flute (grade 7) and guitar to a high standard as well as several other instruments.
- I am an avid climber and particularly enjoy the combination of problem solving with both strength and flexibility training.
- I enjoy reading, especially sci-fi and fantasy works.
- I hold a full UK Drivers License.

References are available upon request.